一旦博士被消灭了
Once the Doctor is exterminated,
我要建立一个新的Dalek种族
I shall build a new race of Daleks.
他们会更致命
They will be even more deadly.
而我 Davros 将成为他们的领袖
And I, Davros, shall be their leader
这一次我们将胜出
This time we shall triumph!
我的Dalek会再一次成为
My Daleks shall once more become
最高等的种族
the Supreme Beings!
- 你在干嘛  - 我怕她尖叫
- What are you doing?! - She was about to scream.
这是Tegan 我的朋友
It's Tegan. She's a friend.
- Turlough... 他是谁 - 别管了 我们快走 马上离开
- Turlough... Who's this? - Never mind. We must get away. Now
- 不跟博士一起吗 - 他在这儿
- Not without the Doctor. - He's here?
在你后面
Look behind you.
脑子里好混乱 我受不鸟惹
I can't stand the confusion in my mind.
快点儿... 放了我
Quickly... Release me.
- 守卫怎么办 - 我们把他们引到这儿
- What about the guards? - We'll call them in here.
你必须替我守着Tardis 军队交给你了
You must secure the Tardis for me. Take the troopers.
遵命
We obey
快进来
In here!
现在怎么办 Dalek的阴影会随时笼罩着我的脑子
Now what? Dalek conditioning could c-cloud my mind at any time.
- 在Tardis里面你会很安全的 - 你不明白 我可能会杀了你
- You'll be safe in the Tardis. - You don't understand. I could kill you.
那就碰碰运气吧
I'll chance it.
- 博士 - 别傻站着 快来帮忙
- Doctor! - Don't just stand there. Come and help.
博士跑掉了 你的军队失败了
The Doctor is free. Your troopers have failed.
你的Dalek又在哪里
And where were your Daleks?
我是Lytton 呼叫特别行动小组
This is Lytton. Call out my Special Guard.
博士, 你看 我们应该离开这里
Doctor, look. We should get out of here.
快
Quickly!
Lytton太强大了 他在抵制我们的控制
Lytton grows too arrogant. His mind resists our control.
一有合适的机会就杀了他
He must be exterminated as soon as it is convenient to the Daleks.
- 我们去哪里 - 地球
- Where are we going? - Earth.
真是最近听到的最好消息
Best news all day.
- 为什么Dalek要救Davros - 为了找到一种病毒的解药
- Why did the Daleks rescue Davros? - To find a cure for a virus.
- 就是那收集器里的东西吗 - 没错
- Is that what's in those cylinders? - Yes.
- 为什么是地球 - 在那儿更安全
- Why Earth? - They were safer there.
通过复制炸弹处理小队 Dalek就可以放心的让他们守卫着
With a duplicated Bomb Disposal Squad, the Daleks have guards above suspicion.
- 设计的真巧妙 - 他们向来很狡猾
- Very neat. - They've lost none of their guile.
你去哪里
Where are you going?
- 刺杀Davros - 博士...
- To kill Davros. - Doctor...!
我必须去 Davros创造了Dalek 不能让他救他们
Davros created the Daleks. He must not save them.
但 谋杀
But, murder?
曾经, 我中止了毁掉Dalek的计划 那是一个错误
Once before, I held back from destroying the Daleks. It was a mistake.
- Davros必须死 - 我跟你一起去
- Davros must die. - I'll come with you.
- 不 - 我知道他在哪儿
- No. - I know where he is.
我也去 我要报仇
I'm coming, too. I'd like my revenge.
好吧 你们在这儿等着 不过 如果Dalek开始攻击
All right. Wait as long as you can but, should the Daleks attack,
- 立刻离开 - 你怎么办
- leave at once. - What about you?
- 这是博士吗 - 犯人很重要
- Could this be the Doctor? - The prisoner is important.
左边那个是Stien, 是我们的特别守卫
The one on the left, Stien, is a Special Guard.
他不应该做守卫工作 除非意外
He wouldn't do escort duty otherwise.
博士和他的Tardis
The Doctor and his Tardis.
非常好
Perfect!
- Lytton. - Davros控制了两个Dalek
- Lytton. - Davros has control of two Daleks.
他们在接待处 想要进博士的Tardis
They are in the reception area, attempting to enter the Doctor's Tardis.
- 必须杀了他们 - 立刻
- You must exterminate them. - At once.
你也要毁掉Davros
You must also destroy Davros.
他不可靠 不能相信他
He is unreliable. He cannot be trusted.
欢迎你, 博士
Welcome, Doctor.
这一刻我等了好久
I have waited many years for this meeting.
- 不好意思让你久等了 - 这是个迟来的惊喜
- I'm sorry to have detained you. - It was a pleasure deferred.
现在 我要你十倍的偿还我曾经历过的精神痛苦
Now here, you will be paid tenfold for the mental agony I suffered.
只能跟你说一件事, Davros 你这番话完全在我意料之中
I'll say one thing for you, Davros. Your conversation is totally predictable.
就像个精神错乱的孩子,你脑中只有复仇和破坏
Like a deranged child, you talk only of revenge and destruction.
这是到达终极力量的唯一路径
It is the only path to ultimate power.
但是何时才是个头儿 还要给活着的人带来多少痛苦
But to what end? More suffering for those who survive?
只有那些反抗我的人才会痛苦
Only for those who resist my will.
- 你想干什么 - 我真希望我不用这么做
- What are you doing? - I hoped I wouldn't have to do this.
Stien 杀掉他
Stien! Kill him!
我来这儿不是为了要当你的犯人, Davros
I'm not here as your prisoner, Davros.
- 而是你的处决者 - 听着...
- But your executioner. - Listen...
我计划完全重新设计Dalek
I had planned to completely redesign the Daleks.
- Kiston会告诉你我说的都是实话 - 确实是这样
- Kiston will confirm I am telling the truth. - It is so.
把它们做的十分残忍是我的错
My mistake was making them totally ruthless.
它把他们的能力限制在杀戮
It restricted their ability to cope with creatures who rely not only on logic,
可他们是有本能和直觉的生物体
but instinct and intuition.
这方面是我想要改正的
That is a factor that I wish to correct.
那么同情心呢  你也为他们设定了那个吗
And compassion? Are they to be programmed for that?
他们会学习着去认识 从情感中提取这种力量
They will learn to recognise the strength that can be drawn from such an emotion.
成为更高效的杀手
To become more efficient killers.
- 成为更有效的武力 - 为了毁灭
- To become a more positive force. - For destruction!
宇宙即战场
The universe is at war.
告诉我哪一个星球的历史不曾有暴行和野心
Name one planet whose history is not littered with atrocities and ambition.
这是通用的行为准则
It is a universal way of life.
我不同意
Which I do not accept.
那你是在否认现实
Then you deny what is real.
加入我们 在新的Dalek军队里你可以统治一切
Join me! You will have total power at the head of a new Dalek army.
- 博士 - 外面 除掉他们
- Doctor. - Outside. Deal with them.
老实说 我不知道要个军队有什么用
To be honest, I wouldn't know what to do with an army.
那是什么
What's that?
博士预先设置了定时器
The Doctor preset the controls on the timer.
- 我们正在飞往地球 - 他不打算回来了
- We're going to Earth. - He didn't intend to return.
- 怎么了 - 我们Dalek的时间走廊里
- What's happening? - We're going down the Dalek's Time Corridor,
被拽回了仓库
being dragged back to the warehouse!
你在犹豫, 博士
You hesitate, Doctor.
如果我是你
If I were you,
我会死掉
I would be dead.
我没你有经验 Davros
I lack your practice, Davros.
你太软弱了 象所有的时间领主一样
You are soft, like all Time Lords.
你们宁愿袖手旁观
You prefer to stand and watch.
行动需要勇气...
Action requires courage...
..这是你所缺少的
..which you lack.
别吵 立刻报告Lytton司令
Don't argue. Report to Commander Lytton at once.
也许我可以说服你们
Perhaps I can convince you.
你一定要这样吗
Did you have to?
帮我把这些尸体藏起来
Help me hide the bodies.
- 你怎么了 - Dalek的控制占上风
- Now what? - The Dalek conditioning is taking hold.
你应该待在Tardis里面
You should have stayed in the Tardis.
缴枪不杀
Drop your guns!
- 没事 是我们的部队 - 是Dalek的部队
- It's all right. They're our troopers. - They're Dalek troopers!
- 待在这儿 - 你需要医疗救治
- Stay there. - You need medical attention.
我控制不了自己的大脑 我很危险 我必须要离开这儿
I can't control my mind. I'm not safe. I must get away from here.
- 等等 我能帮你 - 不要跟着我 我会害死你的
- Wait! I can help you. - Don't follow me.I may cause your death.
蠢货
Imbecile.
你的部队失败了 Davros还活着
Your troopers have failed. Davros still lives.
那就炸掉空间站
Then shoot the space station down.
我要看着他死掉
I must see him dead.
我派了几个Dalek 去完成你失败的任务
I have dispatched Daleks to complete the task you failed.
你必须要做出补偿
You must redeem yourself.
你必须毁掉Davros的Dalek
You must destroy the Daleks of Davros.
- 他们去哪儿了 - 跟着他们去地球
- Where are they? - You must follow them to Earth.
务必杀掉他们
You must exterminate them.
这一点儿都不好 我要更积极些
This isn't any good. I've got to be more positive.
积极点
Positive.
自毁... 我一定要找到自毁系统控制室
Self-destruct... I must find the self-destruct chamber.
- 这太傻了 - 别说话 士兵们可能会听到
- This is lunacy. - Quiet! The soldiers might hear you.
有什么用呢 我们不能再回到Dalek飞船上
What's the point? We can't go back to the Dalek ship.
博士可能会回来 也许有些别的机会 我也不知道
The Doctor may get back. Some other opportunity may arise. I don't know!
完全疯了
Absolute madness.
收集器里的病毒是唯一 能克制Dalek的东西
The virus in those cylinders is the only effective thing to fight the Daleks with.
去 把病毒放到Dalek飞船上
Go. Release the virus in the Dalek ship.
Davros的Dalek
Davros's Daleks?
毁掉它们 这是Dalek元首的命令
Destroy them. The Supreme Dalek's order.
Tardis不在这一层上 我们去其它地方找找
The Tardis is not on this level. We must search elsewhere.
动手
Now!
在你后面
Behind you!
- 真的 一个就够了 - 我们需要另一个
- Surely one's enough! - We need another.
好啦... 我们回到Tardis里
Right... Let's get back to the Tardis.
躲起来
Take cover!
准备降落
We are ready to descend.
继续 消灭一切
Proceed. Everything must be exterminated,
包括Lytton和他的部队
including Lytton and his troopers.
遵命
We obey.
停下
Stop
消灭
Exterminate
我们一定要找到Tardis 那是我们的终极目标
We must find the Tardis. That is our prime mission.
我们必须服从Davros
We must obey Davros.
- 怎么了 - 我们遇袭了
- What is happening? - We are being attacked.
Dalek元首 想毁掉我们
The Supreme Dalek wishes us destroyed.
侵入的Dalek 必须被消灭
The invading Daleks must be exterminated.
Dalek们 到自毁系统控制室
Daleks, to the self-destruct chamber.
敌人闯入了 紧急情况 紧急情况
A hostile has broken in. Emergency Emergency
快阻止他
He must be stopped.
找出叛徒 Dalek的敌人必须要被毁掉
We must find the traitors. The enemy of the Daleks must be destroyed.
我们不是叛徒 我们服务于我们的创造者, Davros.
We are not traitors. We serve our creator, Davros.
Dalek元首是你们的统治者 任何时候都要服从于他
The Supreme Dalek is your ruler. He must be obeyed at all times.
- Davros应该被尊重 - 他必须被消灭
- Davros must be honoured. - He must be exterminated.
没什么能够阻止 Dalek的前进
Nothing must impede the true destiny of the Daleks
你必须被消灭 消灭
You must be exterminated. Exterminated
消灭
Exterminated
- 博士 - 干得好
- Doctor! - Well done.
她想打开那收集器 我担心她会引发传染病
She's been trying to open the cylinder. I warned her she could start an epidemic.
病毒只对Dalek有效 它们遇上会死
The virus attacks only Daleks. Then it will die.
下一层情况怎么样了
What's happening on the next floor?
大餐已经为他们准备好了
Lunch has arrived.
逃生舱准备好了
My escape hatch is prepared.
现在麻烦是Dalek的了
Now for the Daleks.
我没有要求你的协助
I did not summon your assistance.
我们来这儿是为了结果你的
We are here to exterminate you.
- 谁下的命令 - Dalek元首
- By whose order? - The Supreme Dalek.
消灭我 你不过是白白送命罢了
Exterminate me, and you abandon your lives without purpose.
加入到我的队伍 我会让你成为宇宙的统治者
Join me, and I will make you rulers of the universe!
发生故障了
Malfunction
- 紧急情况  - 发生故障了
- EmergencyI - MalfunctionI
你命休矣
Your lives are over!
系统错误
System failureI
开门
Open the doors.
怎么了 我看不到
What is happening? I cannot see.
- 我看不到了  视力受损  - 紧急情况
- I cannot see  My vision is impaired  - Emergency
他们正迈向死亡
They are dying.
你也逃不掉
And so are you.
- 我看不到  - 紧急情况 紧急情况
- I cannot see  - Emergency  Emergency
搞定 我要休息下了
Done it! I must rest.
好累
I'm tired.
Dalek们死掉了
The Daleks are dead.
新的Dalek种族万岁
Long live the new Daleks!
噢...
Oh...!
怎么了
What is happening?
不... 不
No...! No!
怎么可能 我...不...是...Dalek
It cannot be! I...am...not...a...Dalek!
我...怎可能...死
I...cannot...die!
我...是...
I...am...
DAAAAVROSSSS
DAAAAVROSSSS!
- 结束了 - 太可怕了
- It's over. - It was horrible.
至少在Dalek找到解药前地球安全了
The Earth is safe, at least until the Daleks find an antidote.
博士快看
Doctor!Look
你没赢, 博士
You have not won, Doctor.
- 你们不能入侵地地球了 - 你一定是忘了 博士
- You won't be able to invade Earth! - You forget, Doctor.
Dalek不需要入侵
Daleks do not need to invade.
我有复制品
I have my duplicates.
有一些已经被放到 这个星球上的战略位置了
Some have already been placed in strategic positions around the planet.
地球的没落 已经为时不远了
The collapse of Earth society will soon occur.
你的复制品们并不稳定
Your duplicates aren't stable.
Dalek终将胜出
The Daleks will triumph.
我们永不失败
We cannot fail.
Dalek的真实使命是 统治宇宙
The Daleks' true destiny is to rule the universe.
你好, 孩儿们 你们来得正是时候
Hello, boys. Just in time for the fun.
- Dalek飞船被毁了 - 怎么会
- The Dalek ship has been destroyed. - How?
- 空间站上的自毁设备起作用了 - Davros
- The self-destruct device on the station. - Davros?
不,不是...
No, no...
Stien, 我想  最后 他一定做出了选择
Stien, I would think. He must have finally decided which side he was on.
- 所有的复制品都不稳定吗 - 嗯 是的
- Are all the duplicates unstable? - Oh, yes.
是的,给他们时间吧, 最终他们会摆脱Dalek的控制
Yes, given time, they will be free of Dalek control.
- 我们要通知地球上的执政者吗 - 啊 是的 是的 要的 来吧
- Should we inform Earth's authorities? - Ah, yes. Yes, indeed. Come along.
我不跟你们去了
I'm not coming with you.
- 你说什么 - 我累了
- I beg your pardon? - I'm tired of it.
- 什么事情 - 今天死了好多人
- What's the matter? - A lot of good people died today.
- 我很难受 - 你觉得我想让一切发生
- I'm sick of it. - You think I want this?
不是
No.
我只是在想我没法继续这样下去了
I just don't think I can go on.
- 你想待在地球上 - 我阿姨Vanessa
- You want to stay on Earth? - My Aunt Vanessa said,
曾在我最初做空姐时说过,
when I became an air stewardess,
- 如果你觉得自己不再喜欢做这个就放弃吧 - Tegan
-if you stop enjoying it, give it up.-Tegan
这不再有趣了 博士
It's stopped being fun, Doctor!
再见
Goodbye.
Turlough
Turlough?
再见
Goodbye.
我会想你们俩儿的
I'll miss you both.
- 不 不 不要像这样离开 - 我必须离开 对不起
- No! No, don't leave, not like this. - I must. I'm sorry.
再见
Goodbye.
真有点儿,呃, 奇怪
It's, uh, strange.
我是因为类似的原因离开Gallifrey的
I left Gallifrey for similar reasons.
我厌倦了他们的生活方式
I'd grown tired of their lifestyle.
看起来我有必要修正我的路线了
It seems I must mend my ways.
来吧
Come on.
坚强点儿, Tegan.
Brave heart, Tegan.
博士, 我会想你的
Doctor, I will miss you.
#这......是我的党费#
#Zhe Shi Wo De Dang Fei#
（注：Zoe Heriot:S05E07 The Wheel in Space登场 S06E07 The War Games被抹去记忆）
（注：Victoria Waterfield:S04E07 The Evil of the Daleks登场 S05E06 Fury from the Deep离开）
（注：Jamie McCrimmon：S04E04 The Highlanders登场 S06E07 The War Games被抹去记忆 在《两个博士》中客串回归）
（注：第二任博士：S04E01 The Power of the Daleks登场 S06E07 The War Games中因违反不干涉原则而被强制重生）
（注：Ben Jackson：S03E10 The War Machines登场 S04E08 The Faceless Ones离开）
（注：Polly：S03E10 The War Machines登场 S04E08 The Faceless Ones离开）
（注：Sara Kingdom：S03E04 The Daleks' Master Plan中登场）
（注：Katarina：S03E03 The Myth Makers登场 S03E04 The Daleks' Master Plan离开）
（注：Steven Taylor：S02E08 The Chase登场 S03E09 The Savages离开）
（注：Vicki：S02E03 The Rescue登场 S03E03 The Myth Makers离开）
（注：Barbara Wright：S01E01 An Unearthly Child登场 S02E08 The Chase离开）
（注：Ian Chesterton：S01E01 An Unearthly Child登场 S02E08 The Chase离开）
（注：Susan Foreman：S01E01 An Unearthly Child登场 S02E02 The Dalek Invasion of Earth离开 在《五个博士》《时间维度》中客串回归）
（注：第一任博士：S01E01 An Unearthly Child登场 S04E02 The Tenth Planet因受到辐射使其进入重生状态）
#好销魂的叫声#
#What a xiaohun vioce#
#我都想撸了#
#I wanna play LOL#
iCelery军团倾情奉献
神秘博士
第21季 第4集
{\fnMicrosoft YaHei\fs20\bord1\shad2\an8\1c&H000000&\3c&HFFFFFF&\fad(195,60)\move(195,60.8,195,00)}iCelery军团倾情奉献
{\fnMicrosoft YaHei\fs36\bord1\shad2\an8\1c&H000000&\3c&HFFFFFF&\fad(195,190)\move(195,190,195,280)}神秘博士
{\fnMicrosoft YaHei\fs18\bord1\shad2\an8\1c&H000000&\3c&HFFFFFF&\fad(195,230)\move(195,230,195,300)}第21季 第4集
戴立克的复兴
校对：NO MORE
翻译：nancydodo
第四部分
本字幕根据知识共享-署名-相同方式共享-4.0国际（CC-BY-SA4.0)协议发布
http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/deed.zh
翻译：nancydodo 校对：NO MORE
后期：小鱼干 监制：于昊源
iCelery
军团